The S&P 500 is 24 days and Bitcoin I
think it might be as little as 12 days.
Like if you miss the biggest 12 days in
Bitcoin, you miss the return for the
year. Is it too late? Like am I too late
to the party? People basically look at
you like you have three heads. We still
believe we're extremely early. Bitcoin's
16 years old. You know, it's just kind
of really just getting going.
>> Give us your price prediction for the
future. I think the the most powerful
bearish case would be pretty significant
resistance level at we are open to
sucking money out of Ethereum. We are
open to sucking money out of Salana. I
was having a conversation with a fellow
who's done quite well in Bitcoin, one of
these whales. I said, "Geez, man." I'm
like, "How were you able to sit on your
Bitcoin? You're middle class guy. All of
a sudden you're worth $100 million.
Weren't you tempted to ring that
register?" Well, we really try not to be
market timers. We try to be
>> Sean Bill joins us today. He is the CIO
of Blockstream. We're going to get his
outlook on Bitcoin and how his fund is
operating now and what his strategy is
for Bitcoin. I'm David Lynn.
>> Bonnie Chang.
>> Sean, so good to see you. We both share
a macro background except I'm not a
trader. You were.
>> Yep.
>> And you were the first pension fund. You
told me offline. Um you told us you were
the first pens well you were for the
first pension fund to have pitched
Bitcoin to institutional investors.
>> Well we were the first US pension fund
to buy Bitcoin and so we started that
process in 2019 and uh it took about 18
months.
>> Uh you know we what we started doing is
we started bringing in educational
sessions. We had different speakers come
in like Marusco and Anthony Pompiano and
you know Dan Morehead and different
different folks and we would just have
them give an update you know to our
pension boards on why adding Bitcoin to
a portfolio could make sense. And so,
um, you know, what ended up happening
was, um, uh, I don't know, 2021, we
seated a fund for Corbin Capital, which
was a credit, private credit fund,
>> and the folks at Skybridge saw that and
they're like, "Oh, hey, you know, um,
would you guys consider seating a
Bitcoin fund?"
>> Skybridge, Scaramucci Fund.
>> That's right. Yeah. So, Ray Noli,
Scaramucci, all those folks. And so um
uh so we said well you know I don't
think it would pass our board because
we've been trying to socialize this for
quite a while but um we are the largest
US LP and your series G fund and if you
decide you wanted to allocate 15% to
Bitcoin yet your limited partner
agreement allows for that and we would
be very supportive of it and I will
write the memos and kind of you know try
and provide air cover to explain why
we're doing this. And so that's how we
originally got into Bitcoin in 2021. It
was a 45 basis point position.
>> Was it very hard for coni to convince
everybody to be on board? What was the
conversation like?
>> Yeah, so you know I think it was
definitely hard. Um and you know it was
uh a lot of hand ringing when we first
got in a lot of every board meeting you
know what's going on with the Bitcoin?
What's happening here? You know because
you got to remember these folks are uh
they are fiduciaries. they, you know,
need to sign off on these things and,
you know, they have to be able to
explain it to their beneficiaries,
right? Which in our case at the Santa
Clara VTA local 265 pension plan, long
name, uh, were bus drivers, train
operators. You know, these folks were
not people that would normally go out
and buy Bitcoin. Uh, so, you know, we
had to kind of explain it to them. Okay,
here's why we think this is interesting.
We ran uh quite a few similations with
mean variance optimized portfolios that
showed that adding anywhere from 1 to 5%
was actually quite attractive to the
portfolio. When you got above that, it
started to kind of really skew the
returns towards whatever Bitcoin was
doing. So you had to kind of keep it
below that. So our formal first
recommendation was for a 1 to 3%
position in Bitcoin. And uh of course
five years later in December of 2024,
Black Rockck finally came out with their
paper saying that they were at 2% as an
official recommendation for multistrap
managers.
>> Main variance. Are you referring to uh
Marowit's modern portfolio theory?
>> Yeah, exactly. Yeah. So just trying to
optimize the portfolio for the
volatility the um
>> Well, this is an interesting topic on
its own. Let me just segue into that for
just a minute. Okay.
Modern portfolio theory uses
>> uh standard deviation over well returns
over standard deviation so riskadjusted
returns.
>> Bitcoin however has a higher sharp ratio
than all other asset classes.
>> So if you were to use that model the
model should in theory just tell you to
own Bitcoin does it not?
>> That's right. And if you use the sortino
method which uh does not penalize you
for upside volatility because the sharp
ratio just looks at volatility over the
risk-free rate right and says okay
upside downside ball we have to look at
all of it on the sortino ratio we say we
really only care about the downside risk
and so you get actually you got 1.11
currently on the Bitcoin sharp ratio
versus a sortino ratio at 2.42.
So, you know, in theory, the models will
try to overallocate you to Bitcoin
because those ratios are so much
stronger. So, you know, for context, you
know, the S&P 500 is a uh 72.72
uh sharp ratio versus the 1.11 for
Bitcoin
>> and I think the Sorino ratio is 24 2.42
for Bitcoin. I think on the S&P it's
like uh 1.15ish
or so approximately.
>> Sorry, just one more followup and I'll
pass it over. So, so just this is really
interesting for me. So, I'm a pensioner,
right? This is 2019. You're giving me
this model that says we should
overallocate this asset because that's
what modern portfolio theory says we
should do. And I'm telling you, 2019,
you just crashed 80% from the 2017
highs. You're crazy.
>> Yeah. Me, I'm wrong.
>> Yeah. People basically look at you like
you have three heads.
>> They're like, "Uh, what is this guy
talking about?
>> We just crashed 80%. Now you want me to
buy this for my pension?"
>> Yes. Yes. And so, you know, it's very
interesting because pensions uh and our
pension in particular was very much
valueoriented. So we had valueoriented
managers, you know, so the idea of
buying something on a break, you know,
is not necessarily uh out of the realm,
right? It's uh might be a little
counterintuitive to step into a a market
that's down so much,
>> but uh if you're a valueoriented
investor, it makes a lot of sense,
right? You harvest gains from some of
your other markets, maybe in your equity
markets or your fixed income markets,
and then you buy the asset that's on
sale. Um so so you know we did uh when
we looked at the modeling we made sure
that we did constrain the model because
otherwise it would give you just a
really ridiculously large allocation of
Bitcoin and then you know you can't sell
that right nobody's going to want to do
that
>> but we said look we think you know
between 1 to three is pretty manageable
like we can
>> we can manage that risk we can explain
that risk we can make a credible case
for why we should be in that zone and
you have to remember back in these days
you know 2019 2021 you know a lot of
these pension funds were underfunded
And so we felt like there was just this
really asymmetric opportunity with
Bitcoin. Um, you know, you know, a
couple different ways of looking at how
to value it. We'll come to that in a
second, but we thought that, you know,
the downside versus the upside risk was
just very heavily skewed to the upside.
And so if we put in 2% of the the
pension fund, maybe we're risking a 50%
draw from there, right? But, you know,
that's 1%
>> of the portfolio. we can make that back
in 6 weeks on the rest of our portfolio,
right? So, we would recover that loss.
On the flip side, if we were right and
we were, you know, we were talking
about, you know, metaf's law in terms of
the network effect and, you know, the
number of participants on the network,
uh, you know, being squared, right? So,
if there's two of us, the network's
worth four. If there's three of us, the
network's worth nine, etc. So, you can
kind of model it out and it gives you a
very nice pathway of where you think
where where we think Bitcoin prices
could go. And that at that time back in
2019 2021 was forecasting like around
150,000ish right over the next you know
5 to seven years. And so we're like we
think you know we can make a pretty
strong case for that. It was at 7,000
when we were having the conversation. It
went to 17,000 by the time we actually
got into Bitcoin. Now but we still felt
like okay yeah it's probably on its way
to 100 right at a minimum. And uh you
know the other way of framing it if you
want to you know say okay let's let's
look you know maybe back law is not the
way but let's go more macro like okay if
we believe that you know bitcoin is kind
of very comparable to a digital gold in
the sense that's limited supply it's um
you know impossible to make more of it
it's uh convertible into any currency
anywhere in the world uh you know these
characteristics are shared by both gold
and bitcoin uh in that case if we were
to say that it goes to par you know that
was a 10x Right. So, you know, today
Bitcoin sits at a little over 2
trillion. Gold sits at a little over 20
trillion. So, we get this question. You
know, we were on the road. We were
visiting pension funds in in California
two weeks ago. Uh we hit 20 different
pension funds at the State Association
of California Employee Retirement
Systems. Uh about a half a trillion
dollars in that room. Um and you know,
you get the question, is it too late?
Like, am I too late to the party? I'm
like, I don't think so. I mean, like,
you know, we got that question in 2019.
We got that question in 2021. I actually
did a big presentation at Sackers in
2022 where we talked about how we got
into Bitcoin and um you know that was
the impetus of us going back this last
couple weeks ago was they wanted a an
update on that because the climate's
changed, the sentiment's changing and um
you know our our takeaway was you know
it's definitely not too late. If you
look at Bitcoin, um, you know, on the
capital markets, it's just that tiny
little orange dot, right? The other $900
trillion dollars out there of assets,
you know, Bitcoin's that little tiny $2
trillion orange dot in the top left,
right? So, there's a lot of room. We we
still believe we're extremely early. Um,
you know, Bitcoin's 16 years old. You
know, it's just kind of really just
getting going, right? So,
>> since we're talking about price
prediction, give us your price
prediction for the future. I think in
the short term I would be surprised if
Bitcoin was not trading over 200,000
like let's call it the next 6 to 12
months. Um it might be faster than that
because I mean we look at how much the
ETFs are buying they're buying 500,000
coins, right? We got the corporate uh
Bitcoin treasuries buying another
300,000 coins. We got you know what new
new minted coins 165,000 per year. So we
have a huge supply demand imbalance. I'm
really surprised that Bitcoin is still
trading at like 108 109. I'm just
curious. We're at a Bitcoin conference.
>> Actually, there was a sign outside that
says, you know, no cameras, no whatever,
no bears allowed. Know that sign?
>> Okay. But have you met anybody here
that's bearish on Bitcoin besides Peter
Schiff?
>> Um, no, not really. Uh, but I haven't
been seeking them out either. Like, I
mean, there might be a bearish
contingent here, you know, I mean, hey,
you know, contrarian, but I I you know,
there's no natural short in Bitcoin.
>> What would be the bearish case for
Bitcoin? I think the the the most
powerful bearish case would be if like
the US taxing authority decided hey
we're going to tax Bitcoin at 70% or 90%
like what they when when US investors
had overseas accounts in Switzerland and
they said hey you got to bring your
money back into America and if you don't
we're going to tax it at 70%. You have
whatever four four months and if you
don't bring it in in the four months
then we're going to tax it at 90%.
Right? and they just make a punitive.
Something like that would be like what I
would say would be real challenge for
Bitcoin. At least from our perspective
sitting here in America now everybody
outside of America just buy our Bitcoin.
correction.
Now, PowerPoint is the program, but what
we make is a PowerPoint presentation.
free.
Do you think Black Rockck getting into
Bitcoin really helps you or the
institutions to adopt Bitcoin?
>> I think it does. I mean, I think um so I
would say there's kind of two real
critical pivoting pivot points. The one
the first one was when President Trump
came to to Nashville last year at this
conference in Nashville. Um you know I
think that was a major like shift right
in in how the future government was
going to be looking at Bitcoin. I think
the second major shift is when Black
Rockck launched their ETF and then this
thing was the fastest growing ETF to get
to 50 billion, you know, in history,
right? Um, and I think that, you know,
uh, Black Rockck has such a great
reputation out there in terms of
institutional investors. Um, almost
every pension fund, almost every
foundation, every endowment will have
some a fund that's, uh, you know, Black
Rockck fund. And so once you've gone
through that due diligence process to
due diligence a fund with a manager,
it's much easier to add a second fund
from the manager or a third fund or
fourth fund. So I think that having
Black Rockck uh on deck with the product
uh really provides a lot of CYA for
investors that may have to answer to
investment committees to boards, you
know, to oversight organizations. Uh
it's kind of like the old saying with
IBM, you know, nobody gets fired for
buying Black Rockck, you know, uh it's
it's it's a benchmark standard. So
>> after the Bitcoin strategic reserve and
the uh Black Rockck ETF, everyone's
assuming that the institutions are just
going to pour in, but I mean, we're not
saying it at that type of level.
>> I would agree with that. So, we were in
Texas last week talking to the Texas
pensions and you know they're also they
just had their Bitcoin strategic reserve
approved in the Senate
>> and we expect that Governor Abbott will
be signing that in the next week maybe
two weeks you know that that will go
into law. Um it was super interesting.
So we you know when we were talking up
there I I did a poll I pulled the
audience we had 125 people in the
audience. I said how many of you in the
audience own Bitcoin yourselves
personally have exposure to Bitcoin?
could be an ETF, could be direct. And
about half the hands, maybe 40 to 50%
went up. Um, and then we said, "Okay,
now of the folks in the room, how many
of your institutions own Bitcoin?" And
it was like three.
>> Oh.
>> So, it's not there yet. So, you have
like you have like, you know, investment
teams that are becoming very familiar
with it. they're they're kind of, you
know, starting to to get comfortable
with Bitcoin, but the institutions
haven't shown up in a big way yet
>> because
>> well, I think it's um I think it's still
they're still on the learning curve, you
know. Um I think that um you know, for
four years this was off limits. You just
couldn't touch it. You'd have, you know,
people, you know, giving you a hard time
from Washington. Um, but now it's, you
know, it is the doors have opened. So,
people are playing catch-up. They're
trying to get up to speed. You know, we
actually get a lot of requests for
educational sessions. You know, can you
do a, you know, kind of what we were
doing back in 2019 with our pension
board. You know, people are now starting
to ask us if we could do that with them
and help them with their their pension
boards.
>> Well, how would you explain Bitcoin to a
pension board today? Well, I would uh I
would say, you know, it's um it's
electronic money, you know, and I'd say
that uh you know, it's the the real
thing that pushed Bitcoin forward is,
you know, eliminating the double spend,
right? So, that's the differentiator
between prior solutions and
>> which is from a portfolio allocation
standpoint. So, for example,
>> if I were I thought you wanted like
really basic like uh like Bitcoin, but I
guess your audience whoops would
>> Yeah. No, that that that's good, too. I
was wondering like I am a fund and I'm
deciding whether to add Bitcoin to my
portfolio period.
So there's a case to be made for
everything else right now. Bonds I get
that%
NASDAQ. Yeah, you know NASDAQ ETFs,
small caps, large caps depending on your
firm's bias.
>> Even gold it's a diversifier.
>> Mhm.
>> What is the role of Bitcoin then?
>> It's uh so you know so much like gold
it's also a diversifier right? It has a
low correlation to a lot of other assets
and it has a very positively skewed uh
right fat right tail on the bell curve
distribution of returns. So if you look
at uh you know Bitcoin versus the S&P uh
S&P has a pretty normal looking bell
curve but if you look at like a Bitcoin
bell curve I don't know if this will
come in backwards on the on the uh TV
but it's basically a fat right tail. So
it's got a lot more large upside months
than it has on the large downside
months. Okay,
>> so you get this great positive skew. So
going back to that sortino ratio, you
know, because you have that right side
skew of the fat tail, it actually makes
it a very attractive asset to add to a
portfolio. Now, you know, I guess the
second, you know, peeling back the onion
further is, you know, does this um does
this is this our expectation going
forward, right? Do we expect that
Bitcoin will be able to repeat what it
has done in the past? And one thing that
we were we were showing in uh another
presentation with the pensions is you
know as the market cap of bitcoin has
grown the volatility has also been
declining. So if we think about this
most recent selloff you know it was
about 35% pullback right but you know
for a lot of people that have been
around for a long time you you know
maybe been through 85% pullbacks or 75%
pullbacks right but they are the the
pullbacks are getting shallower and
shallower as the market cap gets bigger
and bigger. So you know now that would
also on the flip side of the coin imply
that perhaps the return the upside
return will also be a little more muted.
That's a tricky one. I think that's more
tricky than you know looking at downside
vault. I think that Bitcoin is an asset
that you know just because it is you
know u you know a set supply of 21
million bitcoins. It's kind of got a
little bit of different rules when it
comes to the upside because there's not
as much float. you know, a lot of people
that buy Bitcoin just put it away. They
sit on it. They don't do anything with
it. They just want to own it. They treat
they treat it as a store of value,
right? Um, and so, you know, uh, I'm,
like I said earlier, I'm really
surprised that Bitcoin is not much
higher than it is right now just because
of the supply demand imbalance between
the ETFs and the corporate treasuries
that are buying so much Bitcoin versus
what's being mined.
>> So, why is it you think?
>> I don't know. I think like uh, you know,
that's a good question. uh you know I'm
sure it has something to do with the
market structure you know maybe people
that are uh lightening up at what they
think is a pretty significant resistance
level at 109 that is you know on if you
look at long-term monthly charts that is
a big trend line that comes in above the
market and seems to have been like a
place where some folks are selling uh
that whole one you know 105 109 window
seems to be a pop or sell area
>> is the main goal for pension fund And
the the main goal should be to make
money, right?
>> Yeah. So the the main goal for a pension
fund is be able to kind of meet their
liabilities, right? Because
you know uh when when you establish a
pension fund you're contributing capital
in and the idea is that you know you're
going to be working for 30 years and the
investments are going to increase in
value and actually about 70% of the
future payout that you will be receiving
is generally generated from market
performance. Mhm.
>> So, you know, if let's say for example,
I'm just going to make up a number here
to make this simple math, but let's say
you know, you were going to collect uh
you know, $100,000 in your pension, uh
you would have probably contributed
about 30,000 and that other 70,000
that's paying out your your benefit is
through market appreciation generally
speaking. So, you know, it's important
to have assets that are appreciating.
>> So, Bitcoin is the best performing
asset. Why only two 3%? Well, okay. So,
that's a good question, too. So, and
this is something that we kind of were
trying to back into with the pension
funds is like, okay, what is the right
amount that you can So, you know, if you
think about um uh like the contribution
of a fang stock to a normal portfolio
like a 6040 pension portfolio, it is
approximately 4% on average is the
volatility contribution to the portfolio
from the fang stock. We have seven fang
stocks. we got or you know magnificent
seven they should be saying uh the
magnificent seven so you have seven of
them that's approximately 28% of the
portfolio of all comes from those seven
stocks um now if we were to try to
defend a position in bitcoin if you had
a 2% position in bitcoin you have
approximately about a 5% contribution to
the overall portfolio volatility so you
know you can kind of make a case well if
you're okay with you know Facebook or
you know one of the f magnificent seven
stocks Apple whatever uh you should be
okay with the volatility that's being
introduced by Bitcoin if it's uh sized
similarly. Now that means in that case
it has to be about a 2% position.
>> I want to talk about your new fund. You
have three products yield income and
alpha.
>> Yes.
>> Can you break it down for us?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So you know Blockstream is,
you know, historically been a company
that is this technology service provider
to the Bitcoin ecosystem, right? So,
Blockstream has historically also been
kind of built by solving their own
problems, right? They are old Bitcoiners
that are been around forever and they
come into problems and like, well, how
do we how do we how do we solve this?
Well, we'll just build it.
>> You sound like um Adam back.
>> Yeah. Well, I've been spending a lot of
time with Adam. Yeah. Yeah. Maybe maybe
I've heard his
>> You become the five closest people
around you.
>> Yeah. Right. Right. Yeah. Well, yeah. I
mean, I've been on the road with Adam
for a month. Um,
yeah. Yeah. Uh, so I mean, you know, and
this is one of the really fun things
about this role, like leaving a, you
know, hedge fund to join Blockstream.
It's like, why would you do that? Like,
you're a GP at a hedge fund. You're
making great, you know, great income.
Why Why would you leave that on the
table? You just won multistrat credit
hedge fund of the year. 2022, 2023, back
toback, you beat PIMCO, Bloomberg
Hedgeweek. Um, but uh, every time I'd
talk to the block streamers and I every
time I'd hang up the phone, I was like
I'd say to my wife, I'm like, "Man, that
was an interesting conversation."
>> Like, these these folks are working on
some really interesting challenges and
problems. Uh, that, you know, I mean,
you know, when you're a credit hedge
fund manager, you know, you kind of have
a playbook, you stay in your playbook,
you stay in your swim lane. You know, if
you do everything right, you'll you'll
be the one of the top performing funds
and maybe you'll have Bloomberg
Hedgeweek award, you know. Mhm.
>> Um and so uh uh this is where you know
we're really going into unchartered
territory where you know uh for example
with our Bitcoin yield fund uh you know
I would describe as hey we've got a
machete we're in the jungle and we are
hacking our path through. We are trying
to figure out how can we do this safely
and without risking our Bitcoin because
believe me nobody at blockchain wants to
lose their Bitcoin right and uh we are
our own biggest customer. We eat our own
dog food. Um, you know, so that's that's
what we're working on. So on the on the
Bitcoin yield fund, there's a couple
different ways you can look at this. Um,
and you know, again, I should caveat it
because people like, well, you know, uh,
what kind of what kind of return? Well,
it's a very low return. So on the yield
fund, we're looking at two two to 4%
return. So very very almost like a money
market we're trying to create, you know.
Um, so how do you do that? How do you
get yield on Bitcoin? Well, there's, you
know, certainly options strategies that
people are using to try to do this.
um it can be a little more risky in
terms of you know uh you know the call
side of things getting your Bitcoin
called away um you know but
>> you're selling call options on Bitcoin
is that it
>> is yeah that's a that's a very common
strategy we're we're you know we're
exploring that u but you have to be very
careful about selling upside in Bitcoin
>> you know now if you tell me hey Sean
we're interested in selling puts oh okay
I'm always happy to own Bitcoin on a
break
>> right I'll make that trade all day. Uh
so that one is is a little more easy to
you know to do. Uh but then you also
have other uh opportunities with like
ETPs, right? So we have this huge surge
of growth that you know with the
exchange traded funds and you know the
exchange traded funds uh you know may
have a big flow into the fund and they
may not be able to buy all the bitcoin
in the open market that they need to buy
that day. So they borrow bitcoin on an
overnight revolver, right? And so those
are interesting ways of gap c capturing
yield.
>> Yes.
>> Um you know bitcoin miners, right? you
know those folks uh you know some of
those folks will borrow bitcoin to pay
expenses but understanding and knowing
that they are going to be uh mining and
minting new bitcoins.
>> Why do you think bitcoin miners have
underperformed bitcoin this year?
>> I think it's a very very very capital
intensive business you know and uh you
know uh you know I I've actually
financed a couple of bitcoin miners at
my prior hedge fund uh primaridian
capital management. Um we uh we financed
um uh some some Bitcoin miners up in
Ohio that were connected into a nuclear
power plant. And we did it a little
differently. We were like, "Okay, for
collateral, we don't want the AS6. We
want your commercial grade electrical
equipment, you know, the transformers,
the substation, the midvoltage electric,
etc. We need a we need a perfected lean
on those assets because if you know if
you are getting into going sideways
those are the assets that we could sell
in the secondary market to actually get
our money back. Those Bitcoin and AS6
you know depreciate like like a lead
balloon. So uh so we we did that
approach um and then we took uh some
equity warrants on the on the hold co.
Uh but my my what I came away from
during that whole underwriting
experience is this is it's a very
capital intensive business. It's very
competitive business. You know, your
cost of energy is critical. Uh, you
know, that's why West Texas and these
places are so popular. It's really a
shame that like places like, you know,
Quebec that have all this hydro aren't,
you know, capturing that. Like they
could be building their sovereign, you
know, Bitcoin treasury with, you know,
basically free electricity like Bhutan.
Bhutan is doing that right with Bitier
and those folks. They're doing that.
They're actually making that happen.
>> Um, so, so I think, uh, you know, miners
underperforming. I think um you know I
think it's it's you know if you peel
back the onion is the capital intensity
is just much higher cost of capital.
>> Mhm.
>> You speak Wall Street language. When you
meet Bitcoiners they're in hoodies.
>> Yeah.
>> They are in front of their computers all
day.
>> Yes.
>> Um was there a
>> I'm wearing the suit cuz I had to give a
speech on the stage.
>> I don't normally wear this.
>> You're usually in hoodies.
>> Not a hoodie. Not a hoodie but you know
uh business casual. Okay. Okay.
>> Yeah. I'm not quite uh the hoodie, but
yeah. Uh no, it's true. Yeah.
>> Was it there like a culture shock?
>> Well, I grew up in the Silicon Valley,
so you know, uh I went to high school in
the Silicon Valley. I went to the
Stanford business school, you know, so
I've always been around the Silicon
Valley. My dad was in the technology
industry. Um you know, so I've I I mean
I you know, I remember when Apple was
going public and you know, getting, you
know, I mean, geez, I mean, going back
to like 1976, getting a Commodore PET
computer, right? Right. I mean, this is
like very unusual at that time. Um, and
you know, my dad bringing home a
suitcase that was the first portable
laptop called an Osborne with a little
tiny screen like this big that was green
letters and this crazy huge clunky
keyboard. So, I've always been around
the techies and the Silicon Valley has
changed a lot. I mean, like when we were
there in the 80s, you know, my dad was a
submariner, uh, you know, conservative
guy with General Electric, you know, and
you know, you know, technology oriented.
Uh, but he had a lot of buddies that
were like, man, like like leftover
hippies from the 60s, right? Like, you
know, my dad was very straight lace. So,
like when he put his Birkenstocks on,
you know, he'd have like, you know, his
black business socks or white, you know,
socks would be like, you know, what's
this guy doing? Uh, but, you know, like
the other dudes, uh, you know, would be
uh, further left than my dad in the
politics and what have you, but
everybody was, you know, everybody was
very interested in the technology and
very interested in tinkering and
everybody was pretty pretty mellow on
politics back in those days. Um so you
know uh certainly uh you know having
watched the Silicon Valley evolve over
the years uh you know certainly saw the
hoodie culture come in with Mark
Zuckerberg and those folks and you know
it's uh still there I mean you know
>> going back to the three funds we haven't
talked about the alpha fund.
>> Yeah so the alpha funds u so so we have
um the yield fund that we just talked
about we have an income fund and then we
have an alpha fund. So, the the yield
fund is really kind of targeted towards
like a hodddler or a um like a Bitcoin
treasury company, you know, that type of
folks, okay? Like you're getting zero on
your Bitcoin, but now we can get you
two.
>> Okay? So, they're probably pretty deep
in the Bitcoin world, right? these folks
that want to look at our fund. On the
other side of the extreme, uh the alpha
fund is for people that um you know
maybe have got passive Bitcoin exposure.
So maybe it's a pension fund that has an
ETF exposure with IBIT or you know one
of the other ETFs um and now they've got
their passive slug of of Bitcoin
allocation. They're looking for some
active management around it to
complement that. So to kind of buttress
that that core Bitcoin allocations,
right? And so there we're really focused
on you know um the model our business
model is like very much like a
millennium or 72 citadel where we have
you know siloed trading teams and so
some of those trading teams will be
focused on high frequency trading. Some
of those trading teams will be focused
on options market making, right? And
options are a really good example of
like how inefficient the Bitcoin
ecosystem is because, you know, if you
if you think about an option, as the
maturity goes out, as the strike price
goes up, you should have a very smooth
smile to the curve. But if you look at
like a Bitcoin option curve, it's like,
you know, it's all like, oh jeez, this
thing's all kinkedked and out of whack,
right? So, there's a lot of opportunity
to actually just ARB options prices. Um,
you know, we've all, you know, heard
about the basis trading, right, with the
PERS and the spot. You know, those
trades come and go, but they can be
quite attractive, right, when they're
there. Uh, inter exchange arbitrage.
Surprisingly, every once in a while,
we'll see a gap between Bitfinex and
Coinbase. It could be $375. We're like,
wow, why is this not getting taken out?
Why isn't somebody arbiting this out?
Um, so there's just, you know, these all
these different interesting strategies.
We do relative value between the Bitcoin
treasury companies um and even between
Bitcoin and the Treasury company stock,
right? Um you know, we have, you know,
all kinds of different strategies that
we're working on in the alpha fund. So,
I would say our yield fund for the old
school, you know, Bitcoin and hodlers
and corporate treasuries. Our alpha fund
for the folks that are further along the
journey than most um but maybe, you
know, need to add some kind of active
management to their portfolio. And then
uh our income fund, which is really the
reason why we started the hedge funds,
was the income fund because we could
run, you know, our yield and alpha funds
just out of our treasury. You know, we
could just plug in Bitcoin. Um but when
we thought about one of the biggest
bottlenecks in the ecosystem, it was how
do you unlock
um how do you unlock all this wealth
creation that has happened in the
Bitcoin ecosystem? And we have these
folks that are sitting on tremendous
amounts of Bitcoin that don't want to
sell it and don't want to trigger taxes
and they would actually like to borrow
against their Bitcoin, right? But you
can't put your Bitcoin on deposit with
Meil Lynch. You can't go bring it over
to UBS or uh Goldman Sachs or whatever,
wherever you bank, you know? And you
know, normally we would say, "Oh, hey,
you know, I got my portfolio and I'm
going to cross margin and take a loan
against my portfolio like Elon or some
of these other folks do." And you never
have to sell anything. But that's not
really easy to do if you're in the
Bitcoin world. So, um, we were trying to
think like how do we like catalyze this
and how do we like, you know, act as a
catalyst to kind of speed up the
flywheel, turn the flywheel faster? And
we're like, well, who's naturally long
dollars? Like, who's sitting on dollars?
Well, okay, that would be your sovereign
wealth out of the Middle East and, you
know, your uh pension funds here in the
US, your foundations, your endowments.
Those folks are all generally long
dollars and what kind of investment
vehicle would we need to create to get
them to come into this Bitcoin
ecosystem? Well, in general, they're
most used to like a hedge fund structure
and that hedge fund should be in the
Cayman Islands, right? And that's the
structure that their lawyers are
familiar with. That's the structure that
they like. And so that's where that's
where we decided, okay, let's create a
fund out of the Cayman Islands for the
income strategy. Uh, at a high level,
we're looking at zero for overnight to
12-month loans. We're looking at LTVs
between 25 to 65%. And then we just have
a matrix pricing. So if uh if you say,
hey, I want, you know, uh, a three-month
loan at a 25% LTV, so four times over
collateralized, uh, you know, you're
going to be at the very low end of our
interest rate, you know, matrix. should
be like 7 and a half 8%. Uh if you say,
"Oh, hey Sean, you know what? We want to
go uh 65% LTV for 12 months." Uh then
we're going to be at the higher end, you
know, we think it'll be right around 12.
Um so we kind of were trying to play in
that in that window. We kind of view
the credit markets and Bitcoin being as
being very underdeveloped, right?
There's two point, you know, two two
trillion plus in value in the Bitcoin
ecosystem. Uh but there's only like $16
billion of hedge fund money traded
around in this ecosystem. And a lot of
that it's focused on altcoins. It's not
even focused on Bitcoin. And we think
that in the Bitcoin ecosystem, it might
be as low as maybe 5 billion, right? And
that's why you have some of these
inefficiencies that are occurring in
these markets. Um so so we think that if
we can kind of unlock these uh credit
markets you know uh on both you know
borrowing you know against your bitcoin
or lending your bitcoin it's a good it's
a good service to provide to the bitcoin
ecosystem and then if we can kind of you
know try to tackle the capital market
space with our alpha fund you know again
trying to bring more efficiency to that
market and you know in a perfect world
uh down the road at some point we put
ourselves out of business right these
markets are too efficient there's no
extra alpha, nothing there for us to
capture anymore. But right now, that's
definitely not the case. You know,
>> I know it's Blockstream. I know it's a
bunch of Bitcoiners, but if it was you
personally um starting a new fund, would
you have added altcoins?
>> Um,
you know, we we are open to sucking
money out of Ethereum, you know, through
high frequency trading and then
converted it into Bitcoin. So, you know,
uh we are open to sucking money out of
Salana and then converting it into more
Bitcoin.
>> That is so scary when he says it. I will
suck the money out of Salana.
>> The altcoin vampire fund. That's what
I'm going to call you.
>> Yeah. Well, I mean, you know, I mean,
uh, you know, I mean, we do believe that
Bitcoin is the first mover, has the big
advantage. It's a black hole, and all
these things are going to get sucked
into it over time. Uh so you know in our
mind it's all about how do we get more
Bitcoin? We want more Bitcoin. And so uh
you know uh if we're if we're you know
if we're going into some of these
altcoins you know you know dealing with
the ETH heads and all the problems they
bring into the ecosystem you know then
you know we got to take a toll. We got
to take some money out there and convert
it back into into Bitcoin. So
>> for your alpha fund, I'm just wondering
because you're using Bitcoin to
essentially outperform Bitcoin,
>> timing the markets is probably very
crucial for you. So what are some
important timing indicators that your
fund where your traders look at?
>> Well, we really try not to be kind of
market timers. We try to be time in the
market if that makes sense.
>> We also explain that.
>> I'm jinxed.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, so you know in Bitcoin
uh and this is not uncommon for other
asset classes too like an S&P 500 and
and different things. I think the S&P
500 is 24 days in Bitcoin I think it
might be as little as 12 days. Like if
you miss the biggest 12 days in Bitcoin,
>> you miss the return for the year, right?
So if you're trying to market time, you
know, a market that's got a compound
annual growth rate of over 65%.
You know, uh you got to be very careful
not to miss that upside, right? because
uh you have a very strong tailwind here.
So we think the opportunities are more
in the relative value type of plays like
we were talking about options market
making and and relative value between
Bitcoin treasury companies and you know
high frequency trading where we're in
and out of the market but we're not
really taking you know long short risk
in terms of you know sitting on cash.
Now, you know, is there are there going
to be times where we want to step on the
gas a little, you know, and maybe, you
know, put a little extra long exposure
on? We're pretty bullish on Bitcoin. So,
yes. I mean, you know, that's kind of
like uh the way we look at Bitcoin. Um
but, you know, technical indicators, I
really like Tom Demar's technical
research. Um you know, he's one of my
favorite technicians. Uh we follow him
pretty closely. Um you know, there's
some other other ones that we like to
like Larry Williams. Um, you know, he's
also got some really interesting
research. Um, and then, uh, you know, I
mean, having started out at the Chicago
Board of Trade in 1994, you know, I I
actually took a lot of those classes
with the people that wrote the books.
Uh, you know, so Sheldon Nenberg on
option pricing and volatility theory,
you know, Lawrence McMillan on the
options manual, you know, uh, uh, John
Murphy, you know, on, uh, technical
analysis, and, you know, Steve Nissan on
candlesticks. and I've taken the classes
with all the guys that wrote those books
and so I'm I'm definitely very in tune I
think with you know technical technicals
of the markets and we try to try to take
advantage of that.
>> Earlier you were talking about Bitcoin
treasury companies. We had Simon from
Metaplanet
>> yesterday and there was a news that says
their stock price is six times premium.
>> Um
>> what is a fair value?
Well, it depends how fast they're
growing their Bitcoin stash, right? So,
MetaPlan has been growing their Bitcoin
stash pretty aggressively, right? Now,
if you have So, you know, a good way to
think of that would be, okay, MetaPlan's
one of the newer players on the on the
block started with a relatively small
stash. They've been doing some big, you
know, uh, issuance and buying Bitcoin
with that. Um, you know, go to the other
stream, you know, the Bitcoin pioneer,
Michael Sailor and Strategy is much more
mature company, a much bigger company,
right? And you know they're still
accumulating tremendous amounts of
Bitcoin but as a percentage of their
overall Bitcoin it's a little slower. So
it would have a lower MNAF. So that one
you know I think might be one and a half
two whereas Metaplan's at six. So it
really kind of depends on where they are
in their cycle and the speed and the
consistency of the program to accumulate
more Bitcoin.
>> So it's not fair to compare
>> strategy. Yeah. I think they're just at
different
>> points in their life cycle. You know, I
mean, I think like, you know, uh,
strategy is, you know, I mean, they're I
mean, you know, they are the first
mover. They got the first mover
advantage and they're kind of building
out the whole capital stack, right, with
their, you know, strategy, their strife,
their strike, their Misti, you know,
their uh, convertible notes, their
secured lending notes. I mean, like, you
know, where do you want to be on the
risk curve? Uh, and, you know, Micro
Strategyy's probably got a product for
you.
>> You know,
>> let me let me play for you this clip.
>> Yeah. of Michael Sailor responding to a
question about MNAV going negative.
>> Yeah,
>> respond to that 30 seconds. Yeah,
>> we constructed the company so that the
company can generate yield and generate
gains even at NAV or below NAV. For
example, we have $64 billion of Bitcoin.
If the stock were to trade to a dollar
tomorrow, well, we wouldn't sell the
equity. Duh. We would just sell the
preferred stock. We would be selling
stock overcolateralized 10 to one
against Bitcoin with a 10% yield and we
would generate billions of dollars of
gains selling the preferred or the fixed
income instrument. At some point people
would say wow uh they're generating
gains anyway and then the value would
come back into the equity
>> your reaction to that
>> generate.
>> Yeah. So I mean like um so I think what
um Sailor is saying there is like okay
if the if the common stock price crashes
uh let's say went to one or something
like what he used there uh there are
other instruments that we can provide
that would still be attractive to
investors that we would still be able to
issue stock in this case the preferred
and then we could still go out and buy
Bitcoin and continue to grow our Bitcoin
stash. So I think that's what he's going
after there. I think, you know, there's
a super interesting technical
dislocation in the market with, you
know, convertible debt that you can
issue at 0% interest rate with a
conversion premium that's 35 to 50%. You
know, if you if you say, "Hey, Sean, you
know, I'll give you a billion dollars at
0% interest,
you know, well, yeah, I will go I will
go buy Bitcoin with that." Uh, because
I'm pretty certain I'm going to
outperform zero, right? If I have at
least a fiveyear window to ride through.
Um so I think you know Sailor has uh you
know uh built the full capital stack
really and uh to his point there I think
he's just saying that you know it's not
just issuing equity it could be
preferred it could be you know converts
whatever the market wants he's willing
to work with them on that. The other
interesting thing is on the preferred
that he's talking about there. Let's say
the market does dump and let's say
Bitcoin goes down substantially, right?
Instead of the stock, right? Well, he
can just he can just uh postpone uh you
know and uh delay paying out that
dividend on those preferreds, right?
They will still accumulate. He'll owe
that down the road, but like he won't
get into a cash crunch per se, right? He
won't he can he can uh you know
basically put those on hold. So
>> there is this thing called liquid
network
>> and it has something to do with your T
plus2 sediment.
>> Well
liquid is again block streamers solving
their own problems. So, you know, the
Bitcoin blockchain, you know, block
every 10 minutes, you know, full
transparency, right? So, we know exactly
what Sean bought, you know, when he
bought it, how much he spent on it if we
know his wallet, right? So, the block
streamer is like, gee whiz, like, you
know, could we make a faster settlement?
Could we go to a one minute block and
for settlement and could we
provide confidential transaction
capability so that we don't know what
Sean bought or sold. We just know that
you know money moved from this wallet to
that wallet. And that was kind of the
idea with with the liquid layer 2
network which is I think right now the
second largest L2 on the Bitcoin
protocol after Babylon. Uh I think we
have approximately $3.2 billion dollars
on that chain. We don't really advertise
it a lot or talk about it a lot but it's
you know all Bitcoin native you know
financial products or you know financial
products that were traditional that need
uh kind of a technical update. So like a
good example is we have uh $1.8 billion
of um uh notes from Mexico for small
businesses and you know Mexico is pretty
inefficient. paper is how things were
getting done and they kind of switched
over to docuine and got things tokenized
and put them on liquid and boom this
market just took off and so we have US
banks that are buying you know Mexican
small business loans that are rolled up
and packaged uh on liquid and uh you
know uh just really you know fueling the
democratization of access to capital for
the Mexican you know retail and small
business crowd. So I think um I think
liquid layer 2 I think uh is going to be
something really to keep a close eye on.
I think I've been when I joined we had
and which was seven months ago we had
about 1.6 billion on that chain and it's
you know basically now doubled
uh in six months. So I think we'll be
probably you know probably I would not
be surprised if we overtook Babylon in
the not too distant future.
Go
>> ahead. Adam back talked about when
Bitcoin first came out, people were not
very comfortable with the transparency.
>> There was no privacy. Yes. But now
people are building all these layer twos
to protect their privacy.
>> Mhm.
>> How should we look at it?
>> Which is better? Well, um I think you
know there's certainly a lot of benefits
to the Bitcoin the way it was designed
to provide sunshine on transactions,
right? You know, everybody I think in
the Bitcoin ecosystem knows you do not
want to be doing nefarious business on
the Bitcoin blockchain. Like that's a
really bad idea. Um on the flip side, uh
do I necessarily want people knowing
exactly what's in my bank account? Do I
want people to necessarily have that
visibility? is so if we think about our
regular banking accounts right now you
you know you may know my checking
account number to maybe you sent money
or pulled money from it but you wouldn't
know the balance right and so I think
some of these layer twos are basically
kind of providing some of that
functionality where okay maybe you have
the wallet address but you wouldn't
necessarily have visibility into the
amount of money in the the wallet which
is you know good for privacy I think so
that's I guess that's one of the things
I think the cipher punks which I you
Adam's one of the OGs of the cippher
punk uh crowd. Um I think those folks
really do value privacy, right? They're
all cryptographers and want to protect
their privacy and the freedom of speech
and these things
>> and uh you know I think that's kind of
why you see some of those layer twos
that you know why they were working on
them.
>> Well, I have one more question for you.
Give us one trading mistake you made on
Bitcoin and lessons we can all learn
from that.
>> Oh yeah. Okay. So this is actually a
very interesting question. Mhm. And for
context,
I was having a conversation with a a
fellow who's done quite well in Bitcoin,
one of these whales. And I said, "Geez,
man," I'm like, "How were you able to
sit on your Bitcoin?" Okay, you know,
you're middle class guy. All of a
sudden, you're worth $100 million.
Weren't you tempted to ring that
register? What about when you hit a
billion? Weren't you tempted to ring
that register?
Okay, so you made it past a billion.
Now, when you hit 10 billion, weren't
you kind of tempted to hit that
register? And uh you know, the story
that I was told was that um these folks
that were very early had made this uh
decision to sell some of their bitcoins
to buy whatever it was. Could have been
a car, could have been a nice trip for
the family, but you know, they got in
when Bitcoin was, you know, 10 cents or
a dollar or whatever. And so, hey, when
it hit a dollar, I'm going to sell some
Bitcoin. and buy whatever I was going to
buy. And then, oh, hey, Bitcoin hit $10.
I'm going to sell some Bitcoin and buy
some more stuff. Wow. Okay, now it's at
100 bucks. I I I sold some stuff, but
but geez, every time I sell it, like it
keeps going up, right? So, this is
becoming very expensive purchases. And
so, like those folks were just very
early to get that lesson learned. So,
like for me, I first heard about Bitcoin
in 2014.
um you know I first started buying
Bitcoin in 2016 and so I came into the
picture later right so I I was like uh
you know had had the run up to a th00and
1100 whatever it was and then crashed
down to 250 I had some technical alerts
on the markets by the time I got my
Coinbase account open by the time I got
Bank America to transfer the money and
Coinbase to accept it and let me
actually buy the Bitcoin was at $456
and uh when Bitcoin ran up uh to $12,000
than 600 or whatever it was. Like, ah, I
just made 38 times my money as a macro
investor.
>> That's insane.
>> This is insane. I have to ring the
register.
>> Then I watched it go to 20. I'm like,
"Oh my god, this thing just went to
20,000."
I'm like, "Shit, I got to figure out how
to get back in."
>> Right? And then it crashed down to
3,700, which was my technical level. I'm
like, "Okay, I got my orders in. I'm
buying getting back in." And uh you
know, I'm like, "Okay, I'm just going to
sit tight." And then boom, we're on our
way back up to 20. I'm like, "Okay, this
is probably a double top, right? Being a
technician, it's probably going to be a
double top. Sell it at 20, made another
six times my money, feeling good, and
boom, it pops through. It goes to
60,000." So, I'm like, jeez. I'm like, I
just sat on my original Bitcoin at 450
and just let it This is the going back
to our earlier conversation about time
in the market versus timing the market.
And this was a very painful lesson to
learn, but better to learn it, you know,
earlier than later, right? And um, you
know, so then when it came back down to
17,000, I reload again
>> and that was the last time I sold.
You know,
>> we were talking to Mike Michael Turpin
yesterday and he has a book that talks
about the four seasons in Bitcoin. And
basically, it's been proven many times
that the seasons are correct. And
>> his argument is if you could just sell
in uh summer and buy in winter, you
could have um 4x your Bitcoin amount.
>> I thought I'd go read Mr. Turpin's book,
>> but do you think a regular investor
could do that?
>> Well, you do see some of those types of
patterns in traditional markets. So,
it's certainly possible. I'd have to go
look at it and read it. Um, you know,
uh, you know, there's there are people
that trade this presidential cycles and
they they they sell in May and go away
and, you know, that's that's also like
maybe another version of this, right?
Close to the summer. Um, so, uh, it
wouldn't surprise me if there was some
cycle like that. Um, you know, very hard
though for I think retail folks to stay
disciplined on that. Um, you because if
you're out traveling and you forget
about it and you don't get it back on,
then you're like, "Oh god, you know, now
I got to now I got to pay up, right, to
get it back into this position." So, I
think again for most folks, you know,
dollar cost averaging in uh time in the
market, let it just let it compound. And
we think there's a very strong case for
and I'm not giving investment advice but
but uh we think there's a very strong
case that Bitcoin can 10x from here. You
know million-dollar Bitcoin would not be
surprising to us.
>> All right let's end it on that happy
hopeful note. Thank you very much Sean.
>> Okay. Thanks for having pleasure. Yep.
Thanks for having me. Yep. Thanks for
having me.